<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
                <origin>City of Philadelphia</origin>
		<origin>Pictometry International Corp.</origin>
		<pubdate>20150925</pubdate>
        <title>2015 City of Philadelphia AccuPlus Orthomosaic</title>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>
		  Abstract: 
		  This dataset consists of ortho imagery produced from nadir images captured by Pictometry International covering the City of Philadelphia, PA, approximately 196 sq miles total. Automatic aerial triangulation (AAT) was performed.  The triangulated frames were rectified to a LiDAR derived DEM.  Mosaicing was performed using an automatic seaming algorithm and manually edited to eliminate seams through elevated features where possible. The dataset includes 1024 GeoTIFF files, 1 ECW, and 1 MrSID file. The data was collected at a 3in Ground Sample Distance (GSD) over between April 12 and May 8th, 2015. At the time of capture ground condiitons were leaf-off, snow free, and water was at normal levels.
		  
		  Data Development: 
		  GPS/INS Processing: During the flight, GPS and INS data was logged on board the aircraft. Simultaneously, GPS data was logged by a stationary reference station network on the ground. After completion of the flight, this data was post-processed using Applanix POSPac v7.1 to generate a smoothed best estimate trajectory (SBET).
		  AeroTriangulation:  Imagery was aerotriangulated using Inpho's Match-AT v6.1.
		  Rectification:  Ortho-rectification was performed using Inpho's OrthoMaster v6.1. A LiDAR derived DEM was used as the rectification surface.
		  Mosaicing:  Mosaiking was performed using Inpho's OrthoVista v6.1 and SeamEditor was employed for manual corrections.
		  
		  Key attribute field names and descriptions:
		  N/A
		  
		  Coordinate system:
		  North American Datum 1983, State Plane Pennsylvania South (FIPS 3702), US Survey Feet
		  
		  Thematic mapping:
		  N/A
		  
		  Other Information:
		  Source: Pictometry International Corp.
		  Date: 2015
	  </abstract>
      <purpose>
		Orthogonal image mosaic to support the needs of the City of Philadelphia, PA. Other uses expected.
		Features updated: 09/25/2015
		Attributes updated: 09/25/2015
		Metadata updated: 09/252015
		Update Frequency: None Planned
		Public = N
		</purpose>
    </descript>
	<timeperd>
		<timeinfo>
			<rngdates>
				<begdate>20150412</begdate>
				<enddate>20150508</enddate>
			</rngdates>
		</timeinfo>
		<current>ground condition</current>
	</timeperd>
	<status>
		<progress>Complete</progress>
		<update>Unknown</update>
	</status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-75.322236</westbc>
        <eastbc>-74.951563</eastbc>
        <northbc>40.141140</northbc>
        <southbc>39.823133</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>None</themekt>
        <themekey>City of Philadelphia</themekey>
        <themekey>Pictometry</themekey>
        <themekey>Ortho</themekey>
		<themekey>Mosaic</themekey>
        <themekey>TIFF</themekey>
        <themekey>2015</themekey>
      </theme>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>
		The City of Philadelphia reserves all rights in the GIS database and any data contained therein, and the end user’s use of the data does not constitute a transfer of, nor does the end user receive, any title or interest in the database or any other City data. The City of Philadelphia makes no representation about the accuracy of any specific information in this GIS data and is provided “as is” and without Warranty of any kind. The user of this data will assume complete responsibility for any and all occurrences resulting from its use or display and will hold the City of Philadelphia harmless from any and all claims, demands, liabilities, obligations, damages, suits, judgments or settlements, including reasonable costs and attorneys' fees that arise from use of this data. Access and Use of this dataset is constrained by the license agreements between Pictometry International and the City of Philadelphia, PA.
	</useconst>
    <datacred>
		Pictometry International Corp.
		100 Town Centre Drive, Suite A
		Rochester, NY 14623
		888-771-9714
	</datacred>
  </idinfo>
  <metainfo>
  <metd>20150925</metd>
	<metc>
		<cntinfo>
			<cntorgp>
				<cntorg>Pictometry International Corp.</cntorg>
				<cntper>Jim Kanaley</cntper>
			</cntorgp>
			<cntpos>Project Manager</cntpos>
			<cntaddr>
				<addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype>
				<address>100 Town Centre Drive</address>
				<address>Suite A</address>
				<city>Rochester</city>
				<state>New York</state>
				<postal>14623</postal>
				<country>USA</country>
			</cntaddr>
			<cntvoice>585-486-0093</cntvoice>
			<cntfax>585-486-0098</cntfax>
			<hours>0900-1700 EST</hours>
		</cntinfo>
	</metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <mettc>local time</mettc>
  </metainfo><distinfo><distrib><cntinfo><cntperp><cntorg>Pennsylvania Spatial Data Access (PASDA) </cntorg></cntperp><cntaddr><addrtype>mailing and physical address</addrtype><address>115 Land and Water Building</address><city>University Park</city><state>Pennsylvania</state><postal>16802</postal><country>United States</country></cntaddr><cntvoice>(814) 865 8792</cntvoice><cntemail>(814) 865 8792</cntemail></cntinfo></distrib><distliab>The USER shall indemnify, save harmless, and, if requested, defend those parties involved with the development and distribution of this data, their officers, agents, and employees from and against any suits, claims, or actions for injury, death, or property damage arising out of the use of or any defect in the FILES or any accompanying documentation. Those parties involved with the development and distribution excluded any and all implied warranties, including warranties or merchantability and fitness for a particular purpose and makes no warranty or representation, either express or implied, with respect to the FILES or accompanying documentation, including its quality, performance, merchantability, or fitness for a particular purpose. The FILES and documentation are provided "as is" and the USER assumes the entire risk as to its quality and performance. Those parties involved with the development and distribution of this data will not be liable for any direct, indirect, special, incidental, or consequential damages arising out of the use or inability to use the FILES or any accompanying documentation.</distliab></distinfo>
</metadata>